Hi, I'm here with Richard Fulcher.
大家好 现在我身边的是 Richard Fulcher
Richard is a UX Designer at Google.
Richard 是 Google 的用户体验设计师
Senior UX Designer?
高级用户体验设计师？
>> That's right >> And has been working on UX for
— 是的 — 他从事用户体验相关工作
the last 15 years.
已经有15年了
Thank you for joining us, Richard.
感谢你来到这里 Richard
>> Oh, it's a pleasure to be here today, thanks for having me.
很高兴能够过来 谢谢邀请
>> To get started, can you describe what user experience design is?
一开始 你能向我们介绍下用户体验设计是什么吗？
>> Sure, it's a big umbrella of several related disciplines
当然 它涵盖了很多以体验设计为中心的
that are all focused on the design of experiences
相关学科
to help a individual person achieve some kind of goal.
帮助个人达到某种目标
And that covers a lot of different types of experiences, most commonly we
它包括很多不同类型的体验
think about software design, but it's also things like environment design, and
一般我们会想到的软件设计 但实际上也包括环境设计
maybe the design of physical products.
还有实体产品设计之类
It can even be things like event coordination.
甚至可以是活动协调这些
It's kind of anything that a user experiences,
包括任何可以构建用途体验
that can be constructed for them.
的东西
When I was kind of first taught this, there was kind of five key concepts.
一开始的时候 他们教我说一般有五个关键的概念
It's the study of users and their context,
也就是通过用户及其背景研究
kind of the environment they operate in, in order that we can design tools for
即他们活动的环境 从而设计工具
them achieve tasks that let them complete goals.
帮助他们完成任务 达成目标
So users, contexts, tasks.
所以是用户、背景、任务
>> And goals.
和目标
>> Goals.
目标
>> Okay, so let's start with the user.
好的 那我们先来谈谈用户
Who are they?
他们是谁？
Well, the user is anyone
用户是任何使用你设计的
who's going to use the product of the service that you're designing.
产品或服务的人
And it's really important to remember that, that runs a really wide range.
但一定要记住 这个范围真的很广
It's very easy to kind of, when you're designing,
在设计的时候 你会很容易
just think about designing for yourself.
把用户想成是你自己
For this one super idealized user that you have in mind.
或者是你脑中特别理想化的一个用户
But in reality, you're going to be building this for
但在现实中 你是在为
people with very different levels of experience.
拥有不同体验水平、不同环境、不同背景的人而设计
With different contexts and different backgrounds that affect
而这些不同会影响
how they'll perceive this thing that you built for them.
他们对你的产品的感觉
>> How do I know who the user is?
我怎么知道谁是用户呢？
>> The key for that is something called user research.
关键在于我们所说的用户研究
I think it's kind of most associated with this idea of,
用户研究基本上就是
taking this product you're working on and testing it in some way,
用某种方式测试你正在制作的产品
having a user come in and try to perform a series of tasks that you assign them.
让用户参与进来 完成你让他们完成的一系列任务
And see how they do and see the things that are problems for them.
观察他们会怎么做 以及他们会遇见什么问题
But user research really covers the whole end-to-end
但是用户研究涵盖了产品开发
development of the product.
从头到尾的整个流程
Even before you've drawn your first screen,
即便是在你画第一个页面之前
you can engage with user research to go into your potential users' homes or
你也可以到潜在用户的家里或工作地点
workplaces, to start to understand that context that's important
进行用户研究 了解他们的背景
to the way that they behave and what their goals are.
这对他们的行动以及目标非常重要
And once you've even kind of finished and shipped,
在你完成以及发布产品之后
you can do things like look at logs and try to analyze usage patterns,
你可以看看日志 分析使用模式
see what people are doing with your product.
看看大家会怎么使用你的产品
Perhaps kind of bias towards things that you want them to do more of, or
比如他们会不会更多地沿着你希望的方向使用产品
see areas that they're spending a lot of time in that you haven't anticipated.
还是在你没有预计到的一些地方花费大量时间